peter SAMUEL A.

1st Floor Gidan Sambo, Gusau, Zamfara State Nigeria. +234-806-240-5881, +234-809-463-

OBJECTIVES

SJECTIVES 0471, peterlily75@gmail.com, passionviewsolutions@gmail.com. To build career in the private and third sector (Consulting, Training, Recruiting & NGOs),

To take up challenges in field works and researches in human development issues,

To have a challenging professional work with opportunity for career development and achievement of organizational goals.

SPECIALISATION

- ➤ Economic/Accounting
- Social Work
- Corporate Development

REGIONAL EXPERIENCE

> Africa (Nigeria)

WORKING EXPERIENCE

- > Over 10 years Corporate Experience (Advocacy, Poverty, Entrepreneurship and Development) with various local trainings.
- ➤ Over 10 years Consulting & Training Experience.
- ➤ Over 15 years Organizational Leadership Experience.

AREAS OF SPECIALISATION

- Advocacy (Entrepreneurship and Development),
- Project Management,
- ➤ Human Resource Management and Development
- Project Monitoring, Coordination and Evaluation
- SMEs Development and Management
- School Management and Development
- > Technical Leadership, Team Development (Project Teams, CSOs Networking and Coalition-building)
- Qualitative Research (Data Collection and Analysis)
- Research and Publications
- Procurement and Needs Assessment

- ➤ Logistics (Organizing Workshops and Conferences)
- Tools and Methodologies in Social Research
- ➤ IEC Materials Development and Promotion
- Training and Capacity Building
- > Financial Reporting
- Work Plan
- Leasing

BEHAVIOURS

- Proactive, able to prioritize, take direction and meet deadlines.
- Good interpersonal Skills, able to build relationships and influence others,
- Energetic, like to travel and work long hours,
- Enthusiastic, innovation,
- Open minded, responsible, flexible and tolerant

SKILLS

- Strong technical writing and analytic skills
- Good computer skills (Microsoft Office Packages)
- Team oriented-willing to assist others to develop.
- Strategically oriented in decision making

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Age: 44 yrs. Sex: Male. Nationality: Nigerian. State: Benue. LGA: Otukpo. Languages: English, Idoma (Read and Write), Hausa and Yoruba.

EDUCATION

National Teachers' Institute (Affiliated to Usman Danfodiyo University, Sokoto).

✓ Post Graduate Diploma in Education (PGDE) – 2011

Federal Polytechnic, Offa, Kwara State, Nigeira

- ✓ HND Accounting, Upper Credit Classification 2003
- ✓ OND Accounting, Lower Credit Classification 1999

SEMINARS, WORKSHOPS AND CONFERENCES ATTENDED

- Youth Employment and Livelihood Strategies Organized by Nigerian Institute of Management (Chartered)
- International Conference on Good Governance and Sustainable Development Organized by Institute of Development Administration of Nigeria (IDAN)

JOB EXPERIENCE

S/N	Organization/Position	Responsibilities
1.	Passionview Solutions Ltd	- Managing Partner Northwest Regional Office.
	Abuja-Nigeria	- Program Initiator, Co-ordinator and Management.
	Managing Partners	- Human Resource Outsourcing, Management and Recruitment.
	2010- todate	- Business Development and Management (SMEs).
		- Negotiation of staff salary and other legal entitlement.
		- Act on-behalf of the firm in any other business matters.
		- Head Consultant to Alkali Mika'ilu International Schools, Gusau
		(Ongoing).
		- Principal Consultant to Leadspring International Schools, Gusau
		(Ongoing).
2.	Eagle Lead Development	- Executive Secretary Nigeria Office
	Initiative, Abuja – Nigeria	- Handles the secretariat affairs of the Organization.
	Project Manager	- Manages the organization program implementation.
	2019 -date	- Developing Programmatic Procedures
		 Coordinates ELDI Yearly programs and events in consultation
		with the Executive Director.
		- Coordinated the KP component intervention with Wave Makers
		Initiative, Kaduna.
		- Gender and Equity Focal point for ELDI.
3	Zamfara State Directorate	- Management of AGMEIS Registration Portal.
	of Skills Acquisition	- Handles Trainings and business plan writing for all prospective
	(ZSDA),	Loan Applicants.
	Gidan Dawa, Gusau,	- Monitor and evaluate the day-to-day operation of the program.
	Zamfara State.	- Handles all complains and concerns on the program.
	Position Held: Principal	
	Consultant	
4.	Cinergi Alternatives	- Planning and Arrangement of Seminars, Workshops, Conferences,
	Lagos-Nigeria.	Summits etc.
	Business Dev. Officer	- Training of staff
	2007- 2010	- Human Resource Management, Outsourcing and Recruitments
		- Head Consultant to Institute of Comprehensive Education (I.C.E),
		Gusau
5.	D-Angels Global Services	- Project Planning, Management, Monitoring & Evaluation
	(Nig)	- Training, Research and Documentation, Formative Assessment
	Ltd, Lagos-Nigeria	(CPMS). Inventory management and Accountability
	Program Officer	- Inventory management and Accountability.
_	2006-2007	- Staff management, procedures and practices
6.	Total Life Health	- Instituted proper way of setting non-profit organization accounting
	International	records.
	Gusau - Nigeria.	- Prepare Budget, Expenditure and Income Statement.
	Accountant	- Prepare account reconciliation statements.
	2004-2005	 Advisory Capacity to Executive Director and Board in matter

		relating to Finance
7.	Women in Empowerment	- Plan implement and monitor programs of the NGO
	and	- Capacity Building.
	Gender Action (WEGA)	- Liaise with communities/grass root women to find possible ways
	Gusau-Nigeria	of collaboration.
	[Resource and Concept	- Develop proposals and implementation, plans for field programs.
	Director]	- Develop. Pre-test and produce information, Education and
		Communication (IEC)
8.	Zamfara State Investment	- Research development on economic potentials of Zamfara state.
	and	- Publication of the above project work.
	Property Development	- Research officer to the project
	Company	
	Limited. Gusau-Nigeira	
	Company Rep.	
	2007	
9.	National Youth Services	Personnel Assistant Officer, Ministry of Commerce, Industry and
	Corps	Tourism. Gusau, Zamfara State.
	(NYSC) Sept 2004 – Aug	
	2005	
10.	Industrial training (IT)	Supply Officer, NNPC Ilorin Depot, Oke-Oyi, Kwara State. 1999-2000.

HOBBIES/TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

- Creative Writing & Researching: Learning New Things: Browsing/Stuffing
- Computer Training: Desktop Publishing, Volunteer and Charity activities,
- **Traveling:** Traveled widely within Nigeria.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION AND AFFILIATION

- Certified Management Consultant- Institute of Management Consultant, Nigeria
- **Certified Recruitment Professional,** Institute of Professional Recruitment Consultants, Nigeria & UK
- Senior Member, Institute of Information and Strategy Management, Nigeria.

REFEREES

(1) Daniel Jonathan

Managing Director Cinergi Alternative Idea Ltd No. 64/66, Alh. Asani Salami Plaza, Ojuelegba Rd, S/L, Lagos-Nigeria Email: kilbaya@gmail.com

Tel: +234-809-766-1527

(2) Benjamin A. Adekola

Adekola Global Ltd 5 Park Road, Gusau Zamfara State Nigeria.

Email: sojinuro@yahoo.com
Tel: +234-083-603-0220